Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 23.
We are going to solve the Fibonacci series and recursion.
So how Fibonacci method in recursion works, this is the function we have.
The main method here in Java.
So we are going to execute it in the main by passing an equal to five to Fibonacci of an OK.
So we are going to find the Fibonacci of five.
But first, what is Fibonacci?
The Fibonacci numbers are the numbers in the following integer sequence.
We have zero.
This is the first elementary branch of one is zero for the Fibonacci story of the first element.
This is the first element in this series.
And the second element, third and fourth, fifth and so on.
OK.
So Fibonacci of n any numbers equals Fibonacci of and minus one plus and minus two is the sum of the
last two elements before that element.
So if we have f of five here, equal f of four plus f of three with seed values, f of zero, equal
to zero and f of one equal to one, we start f of zero is zero here.
This is that zero.
This is the one.
This is then next two and three.
For.
And a 5:00 a.m. game Fibonacci method, and we have a Fibonacci number and integer methods returning
integer, and we have an integer passed into the parameter, so we are checking if an equal or less
than one retired and retired and an OK otherwise return Fibonacci and minus one plus Fibonacci of and
minus two.
OK, so.
If here and equal to zero, it were return zero F and equal to one, it will return one.
Otherwise, it will return for both negative and minus one loss from a negative and minus.
OK, so let's go and see how it works and.
A real life and recursion.
You ask it in an interview and this question have been asked in an interview to a big company, OK,
so please pay attention how this works.
We have seen that the general formula that we are going to follow is f of an equal f of and minus one
plus f of and minus two and the seat values here f of zero equal to zero and f of one equal to one.
OK.
So we are going to solve f of Fibonacci of five.
We are asked to solve f Fibonacci of five, which is equal to Fibonacci of and minus one and equal to
five.
So there's four and Fibonacci of.
And minus two, which is three.
OK, so.
There is a very big track, and you are asking here many times because it is.
About understanding your understanding that encouraging.
OK, so here we are going to start solving the Fibonacci of four and we get the result like a number.
For example, five or three or whatever.
And then we move to Fibonacci of three.
We are not going to solve this simultaneously.
This is going to be solved and then getting the result and then moving to Fibonacci of three and then
getting the result to be added together.
This is very important.
I need from you to pay attention for with me because it's very important the trick here and it is about
understanding the recursion algorithms and how it works.
So we start with Fibonacci of three.
OK.
With Fibonacci, of course.
So.
This is the Fibonacci offer.
OK?
We start calculating Fibonacci of four is equal to Fibonacci of three plus Fibonacci off two.
OK, I need it from you to understand that this will follow the same rule that we have mentioned before
Fibonacci of three as being calculated first.
And then when we have a result here, it will be executing the Fibonacci of two and finding that Fibonacci
of two, self Fibonacci of three.
Here, Fibonacci of three is equal to Fibonacci of two plus Fibonacci of one.
OK, now again Fibonacci of two.
Equal to Fibonacci of one plus Fibonacci of zero.
OK, now we need to calculate Fibonacci of one, Fibonacci of one is one because we have seen that Fibonacci
of one equal to one and Banerjee of zero is equal to zero.
And Fibonacci of zero.
Equal to zero.
OK, now.
We are going to substitute these values because we have ended here.
OK, one plus zero.
Is equal to zero.
Sorry, one, oops.
This is a very basic mathematic.
OK, so one.
So the result of a Fibonacci tool is equal to one.
OK.
OK, guys.
This is the Fibonacci of two.
Now we get one and we substitute it here.
Sell Fibonacci of three is equal Fibonacci of two, plus Fibonacci of one.
Fibonacci of two is equal to one.
And we are going to calculate the Wenatchee of one now, but since Fibonacci of one is one.
So we are going to get it back.
Therefore, Fibonacci of three is equal to one plus one, which is equal to two.
So this is the Fibonacci of the three.
Now we substitute Fibonacci of three and Fibonacci of three, and we put it two.
Now we need to start with another part, which is Fibonacci of two.
OK.
So.
Let me choose another.
Color self-reported that you have to.
Is being calculated here.
So it is equal to Fibonacci of one less Fibonacci of the zero Fibonacci of one.
As one and Fibonacci of zero equal to zero.
So one is being replaced and zero is re being replaced, one plus zero equal to one.
So this is the Fibonacci of two.
OK.
Therefore, we have here Fibonacci of three is equal to two, plus Fibonacci of two is equal to one.
Therefore, we have calculated f2.2 of three, which is three.
So we are going to replace Fibonacci of three or sorry from a network of four with three.
OK.
This is the first segment.
This is the first part.
OK.
This is the first part that we have solved.
We move now since we have three.
We move now to the Fibonacci of three and the second part of the Fibonacci of four a five.
OK.
So.
Fibonacci of three, this is being calculated again and again, it will not depend on the previous calculation,
it go and start calculating it from the beginning.
OK, so Fibonacci offer three is.
Fibonacci of three signature of two, plus Fibonacci of one.
Fibonacci of Do as Fibonacci of one plus through nature of zero and Fibonacci of one is one, and Fibonacci
of zero is equal to zero.
Being replaced here one is replaced by signature with one and zero by zero.
This is one plus zero equal to one.
So Fibonacci of two is equal to one.
OK.
Sorry.
Now, Fibonacci of one is equal to one because.
Components of one is equal to one.
OK.
This one will be replaced here.
So one is here and one is here, so Fibonacci of three is equal to two.
One plus one is equal to two.
Therefore, this is being replaced here.
So.
Fibonacci of five.
Going back to our main function from one that year of four is equal to three.
Plus.
Two, three, four.
Not your four and one of three is being replaced by two, which is equal to five.
OK.
This is how we solve their Fibonacci recursion questions.
It's very simple.
I need from you to practice more.
Go ahead and take an example.
Like Fibonacci of six nuts, you have seven, eight and so on, and try to find the series in the same
way I need from you.
Also to write these notes on your copy book in order to review for that interviews and the exams.
One last thing I need also from you is to understand how recursion works.
It starts by like calculating that, for example, Fibonacci of five equals four plus three Fibonacci
of four plus four minutes.
You have three.
It starts calculating that Fibonacci of four.
And then when it get the result, it starts again with Fibonacci of three.
This is the point.